Day 1
Day 2, Day 3, Day 4, Day 5
Shut up! I do have a grandpa!
As if an old man could give birth to a wooden puppet!
Yeah, that's right!
I'm Grandpa's boy!
Yay! My puppet!
Why, you...!
What?
Help! Help me!
Goal!
Help! Don't score!
(Children's sorrowful laughter)
Heh, but look!
Mokku, why don't you help him, huh? Mokku— Shut up! It's his fault! What do I care?!
Mokku, you'll never become human acting like that!
Human?
That's right. What will happen if you don't save him?
There's no one else who can swim!
Ah, Box!
Box!
What's wrong?!
Hurry! Hurry! Hurry!
Hurry!
Does Cathy really love me?
I don't care even if you're like a mother. No, I love you. I love you.
And I will stay by your side.
[[NO AUDIO]]
It wasn't me. He's the one to blame for doing that first.
It's not my fault! He's the one who fell in.
Cheer up. Don't be so down.
So it's really not my fault?
But...
That's right, Mokku. Come on, Mokku.
There's no need to brood over it.
That boy Cole fell into the river because the bridge was broken.
You bravely jumped into the river to save him when no one else could.
Of course I did. Huh? It doesn't bother me at all.
Then let's hurry home. Grandpa is worried about you.
Why are you still moping around? It wasn't your fault. Brooding won't change anything.
Shut up!
Stop putting on a tough act. You play pranks, but deep down, Mokku is a kind-hearted boy.
Stop it! Get lost, all of you!
[[NO AUDIO]]
Hey, Mokku, what are you trying to do?
I'm going to take Cole's place. —Huh? What did you say?
If I become Cole,
even Cole's mother will be happy.
Don't be foolish. It's not that easy to become someone else's child.
Shut up! That way I'll have a mama, too, and maybe I could even become human!
Good grief. Why do you always think only of yourself?
Be quiet! You nag and complain way too much anyway!
Right?!
What an idiot. He's only going to cause Cole's mother more grief.
Welcome home.
(Sad music)
Cole...
Cole?
I'm such a fool... As if Cole would ever come home.
Who's there?
Oh... Who are you?
I came to see you.
I was swept down the river with Cole.
I, um... thought I could take Cole's place and comfort you, ma'am... Here.
Get out! I don't ever want to see your face!
Ma'am!
Get out!
I know the truth!
If you hadn't thrown that stone, Cole wouldn't have slipped and fallen into the river!
Get out of here right now!
And I'm going to kill her.
She died in my place.
She's a puppet girl.
Oh, it started raining. How nice.
Please rest a little longer.
I'll be back.
Auntie!
Where did he go in this rain?
Again...
Looks like he came back. An old woman like me being so foolish... I feel terrible about what I did to him.
In a place like this...
What a silly boy...
Huh?
Are you awake? Here, your lunch is ready.
Wash your face and put this on.
I think it will fit you perfectly.
What's the matter? Hurry up or you'll be late for school.
A-Auntie, are you forgiving me?
Thank you, Auntie! I'll be a good boy, I promise! I really promise!
Whoa, incredible!
This is awesome!
Hey, Mokku! You can't even taste anything anyway, can you? Let me eat it!
Let's trade lunches!
Looks so good. Let me have some too!
No way! Like I'd ever give any to you guys!
Hand it over!
Like hell I will!
Whoops, take that!
Why, you little...!
Hah!
Ow!
Oww!
Now then...
Welcome home, Cole.
What happened to your clothes?
You've been fighting, haven't you?
Cole loved mischief too, but he was never bad enough to tear his clothes to shreds like this.
Oh well.
By the way, did you enjoy your lunch?
Yeah.
I'm glad. Now, give me the basket.
What's wrong? Come on, give it here.
Here.
I'm sorry. Everyone tried to take my lunch, so...
You ruin everything that belonged to Cole, don't you?
Huh?
Eat up. They're all Cole's favorites.
Mokku, what would you like on your bread? Cole loved jam.
He'd take huge bites, too.
Here, I spread plenty of jam on it, just like Cole liked.
What's wrong? You're a strange boy.
Mokku!
I don't want that stuff!
Mokku, that is unacceptable! Cole was a much better boy.
Stop it!
Cole! Cole! Cole!
I'm not Cole!
I'm Mokku! My name is Mokku!
(Camera shutter clicks)
Ma'am, I'm sorry about earlier.
It's all right, Mokku. Please forgive me for hurting your feelings. I'm truly grateful for your kind heart.
It's getting late. Good night, Mokku.
Mokku, where are you right now?
Grandpa...
(Woman laughing)
I'm just a puppet anyway! I'm not a human child!
Everyone's like that. Just because I'm a puppet with no mother, they treat me like I don't matter.
Cole, Crank, all of them...
But I want a mother, too!
I want to be a human child!
Stupid! Stupid! Stupid!
Huh?
Mokku... You understand what I told you now, don't you? If you stay here any longer, you'll only cause that lady more suffering.
I don't want to hear your preaching, so just shut up! No matter how hard you try, you can't comfort me.
So you're going back to your big brother.
Mokku, please don't leave me. Don't leave me all alone.
Mokku!
Was it just a dream...
Big Brother!
Mokku! Mokku came back!
He fell!
Grandpa, I'm sorry for not coming home. Are you mad at me, Grandpa?
No, I'm not.
Really?
Truly. But I was very lonely. Still, I'm so glad. You have no idea how happy I am.
Grandpa.
Forgive me. Because we're so poor, I can't even pack you a lunch.
I'm a puppet, so I don't need to eat. Just being by your side is enough.
I'm leaving now!
Be careful out there.
Mokku.
Mokku, you must be angry with me for hitting you.
I couldn't take Cole's place after all. I'm sorry.
Here, this is your lunch.
Thank you, Mokku. Thanks to you, I can keep living without grieving forever.
Really? Do you truly mean it?
Promise me you won't be sad anymore.
I promise. In exchange, Mokku, you must study hard and be a good boy.
Yeah. And I'll become human, just like Cole.
Thank you.
Mama.
I've always wanted to call you that just once.
It's a promise, no more crying.
See, even I'm—
(laughter)
See?
Goodbye, Mokku.
(laughter)
Goodbye, Mama.
Mama...
Just as Nora the stray cat said, Mokku is tied to a cross to begin his training to become human.
By the time he realizes it's a wicked scheme by Kenken and his gang, it's too late, and the scorching sun leaves him utterly exhausted.
On top of that, battered by lightning and a great flood, will Mokku have the strength left to survive this ordeal?
Look forward to next week's Kashi no Ki Mokku!